Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory8 Mss.B.B61.inventory08
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents L
  - Learned M.D. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 15; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Nov. 18; 1p.
  - Leary, D.B. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 3; 1p.
    - D.B. Leary -- to S. Wallach, 1935 Oct.; 1p.
  - Leavitt, A.B. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1908 June 16
  - Leavitt, F.H. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 16; 1p.
  - Lebbelor, Gerda (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1909 May 25
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 23; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Nov. 30
    - G. Lebbelor -- from A.C. Haddon, 1910 Dec. 15
  - Lebenson, A.H. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1936 June 22; 1p.
  - Lebmann, W. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1912 Jan. 8
  - Lecointe, Georges (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1907 Dec. 18
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 20; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 23
  - Lecour, J.H. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1910 June 3
  - LeCron, J.D. (Box 55)
    - J.D. LeCron -- to L.C. Barth, 1940 Jan. 18; 1p.
  - Leden (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 22; 1p.
  - Lederer, E. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1933 June 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 20; 1p.
  - Ledón, LuC-s C. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1914 Oct. 29; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1916 Jan. 18; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1916 Jan. 24; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1916 Jan. 24; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Jan. 14
    - To Boas, 1914 Nov. 10
  - Lee, Amgoza (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1918 Nov. 21; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Apr. 14; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Nov. 26; 2p.
  - Lee, Cuthbert (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1939 Oct. 18; 1p.
      (Enc: American journals and the war.)
  - Lee, F.S. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1908 May 29
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 25
  - Lee, Josephine (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1941 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - J. Lee -- to D. Trachtberg, 1940 Jan. 30; 1p.
  - Lee, T.S. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1908 May 28
  - Leege, Willy (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 30; 1p.
  - Leeson, B.W. (Box 55)
    See Lesson, B.W.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 20; 2p.
  - Lefahrt, H. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 28; 1p.
  - LeFevre, L. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1926 Sept. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept. 10; 1p.
  - Lefkowitz, Abraham (Box 55)
    - A. Lefkowitz -- from M.I. Finkelstein, 1939 Oct. 21
  - Leheller, R. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec. 12
  - Lehmacher, Franz (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 20; 1p.
  - Lehman, H.H. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1925 Feb. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Aug. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Aug. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Aug. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Sept. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1899 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - H.H. Lehman -- from Gardner Murphy, 1936 July 10
    - (Enc. with Murphy, Gardner, July 10, 1936)
  - Lehmann, Carl (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1893 Jan. 12
    - To Boas, 1893 Jan. 12
  - Lehmann, E. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1912 Aug. 5
  - Lehmann, Heinz (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1933 July 11; 1p.
  - Lehmann, Rudolf (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1910 Jan. 28; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 21; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 31; 6p.
    - To Boas, 15 Aug. 1920; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 29; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1922 Aug. 31; 4p.
    - R. Lehmann -- from Frischersen? KC6hler, 1919 Nov. 24; 3p.
    - R. Lehmann, -- to Veit & Co., 1913 Oct. 11; 4p.
    - R. Lehmann, -- to Veit & Co., 1913 Oct. 26; 4p.
    - R. Lehmann -- from Veit & Co., 1913 Oct. 20
    - R. Lehmann -- from Veit & Co., 1913 Oct. 21
    - R. Lehmann -- from Veit & Co., 1913 Oct. 22
    - R. Lehmann -- from Veit & Co., 1913 Oct. 28
    - R. Lehmann -- from Veit & Co., 1913 Oct. 29
  - Lehmann, Mrs. R. (Box 55)
    - Mrs. R. Lehmann -- from L. v.d. Steiney, 1931 Dec. 21
    - Mrs. R. Lehmann -- from L. v.d. Steiney, 1932 Mar. 28
  - Lehmann, Walter (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1906 Oct. 24
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 4
    - From Boas, 1907 May 6
    - From Boas, 1908 Jan. 13
    - From Boas, 1910 Mar. 14
    - From Boas, 1912 June 16
    - From Boas, 1912 Sept. 2
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 18; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 9; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1914 Feb. 21
    - From Boas, 1920 Jan. 15; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Dec. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Sept. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Dec. 5; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Dec. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Aug. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 July 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 22; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 18; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Sept. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Jan. 8
    - To Boas, 1912 June 18
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 23; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 9
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 23; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Aug. 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Sept. 13; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Nov. 6; 2p.
    - (Enc: Ergebnis der phonetischen Kommission des 21. Internat. Am. Kgr. GC6teborg 1924.), 1925 Jan. 7; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Mar. 13; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1925 May 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 July 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 20; 2p.
    - W. Lehmann -- to Hofe, von, 1933 Aug. 30; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Schneider, K. Sept. 6, 1933), 1933 Aug. 25; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Schneider, K., Sept. 6, 1933)
    - W. Lehmann -- from Strecker & SchrC6der, 1921 Nov. 16; 2p.
  - Lehmann-Haupt, C.F. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1933 Sept. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 May 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Apr. 17; 2p.
  - Lehmann-Haupt, H. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct. 4; 1p.
  - Lehmann-Haupt, K.F. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 18; 1p.
  - Lehmann-Nietsche, Robert (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1908 June 6; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 16
    - From Boas, 1920 Jan. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Apr. 4; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 July 18; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 July 28; 1p.
  - Lehsten, E.E. (Box 55)
    - E.E. Lehsten -- to Mayor J.C. Cadien, 1917 June 14; 2p.
  - Lehuar (?) (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1899 Feb. 25
  - Leibner, Mildred C. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 May 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 May 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 June 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Sept. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Oct. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 May 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 May 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 June 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 June 23; 1p.
    - (Enc: List of Anti-Fascist organizations. Clippings Draft of a letter), 1936 July 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 6; 1p.
    - (Enc: American Committee for Anti-Nazi Literature. Executive Committee. Minutes.), 1936 Sept. 3; 1p.
    - (Enc: American Committee for Anti-Nazi Literature. Executive Committee. Minutes. Aug. 31, 1936), 1936 Sept. 21; 1p.
    - (Enc: American Committee for Anti-Nazi Literature Executive Committee. Minutes. Sept. 14, 1936.), 1936 Oct. 20; 1p.
    - (Enc: Program), 1936 Oct. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Nov. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 June 5; 1p.
  - Leidingen (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1924 Aug. 19; 1p.
  - Leigh, R.D. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 3; telegram
  - Leiper, H.S. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1938 Mar. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Apr. 21; 1p.
  - Leipzig, Germany (Box 55)
    See Schinke
  - Leipzig, Museum für Völkerkunde (H. Zehn) (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1898 Sept. 1
  - Leipzig, Schriftleitung der Illustrierten Zeitung (Box 55)
  - Leipziger, Henry M. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1910 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1913 May 28
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 16
    - From Boas, 1914 Mar. 20
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 4
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 12
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 26; postcard
    - To Boas, 1914 Mar. 12; postcard
    - To Boas, 1914 Mar. 5; postcard
  - Leisk, H.V. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 19; 1p.
  - Leissner, Adele (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1931 Dec. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 7; 1p.
  - Leite, E. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1936 Nov. 9; 1p.
  - Leite, J. & Cia. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 28; bill
  - Leitner, E.H. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1992 Oct. 30
  - Leitner, R. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 2; 1p.
  - Leitner, S. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 9
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec. 6
  - Lejuné Flores y Cía (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 29
  - Leksell, I. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1924 Sept. 14; 2p.
  - Leland, Waldo G. (Box 55)
    - 1925 Dec. 14, 2p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Jan. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 6; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Apr. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 25; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 27; teleg.
    - From Boas, 1929 May 7; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Dec. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Dec. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Sept. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Sept. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Jan. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 June 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 22; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Dec. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Jan. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Apr. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 May 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 May 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 July 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Aug. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Dec. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Jan. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - (Enc: Amer, Council of Learned Societies. Comm. on Amer. Indian languages., Jan. 1941)
    - From Boas, 1941 Feb. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 June 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 June 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Sept. 29; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Oct. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Jan. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 5; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Apr. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 July 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Nov. 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 24; teleg.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 23; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 June 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Aug. 4; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Sept. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Oct. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 May 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Jan. 19; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 6; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Nov. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 25; 1p.
    - (Enc: Committee on Research in Native Amer. Languages - List of studies.), 1938 Mar. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 July 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Jan. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 July 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Oct. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Dec. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - W.G. Leland -- to Amer. Council of Learned Societies, 1938 Feb. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - W.G. Leland -- from M.J. Andrade, 1932 Oct. 15
    - W.G. Leland -- to E.P. Boas, 1942 Dec. 24; 1p.
    - W.G. Leland -- to F. Boas & R.G. Kent, 1928 Apr. 18; 1p.
    - (Enc: Leland, W.G. to Keppel, F.P. 3p. Leland, W.G. to Keppel, F.P. 2p.), Apr. 19, 1928 Apr. 1-
    - W.G. Leland -- to F.P. Keppel, 1928 Apr. 1-; 2p.
      - (Enc. originally with Leland to Boas, F. & Kent, Apr. 18, 1928)
    - W.G. Leland -- to F.P. Keppel, 1928 Apr. 19; 3p.
      - (Enc. originally with Leland to Boas, F. & Kent, Apr. 18, 1928)
    - W.G. Leland -- to E. Sapir, 1936 Dec. 18; 2p.
    - W.G. Leland -- to E. Sapir, 1937 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - W.G. Leland -- from E. Sapir, 1936 Dec. 23
  - Lemcke & Büchner (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 19; 1p.
      (Enc: List of publications wanted by Columbia Univ. Press.)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Aug. 15
      See Hartog, Alfred
  - Lemstrom, A. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 21
  - L'Engle, Tracy (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1927 Oct. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Oct. 5; 1p.
  - Lengyel, Emil (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 15; 1p.
  - von Lenhoosek, M. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1922 Jan. 30; 1p.
  - Leningrad. Institute of living languages of the East. Library (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 11; 1p.
  - Leningrad. Museum of anthropology and ethnology. Library (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 11; 1p.
  - Leningrad University (Box 55)
    - From S.P. Duggan, 1928 Nov. 19
  - Lennard, Lotte (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1931 June 1; 1p.
  - Lenz, Rodolfo (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1910 Aug. 19
    - From Boas, 1912 June 15
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 16
    - From Boas, 1918 Jan. 30; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Jan. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 May 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1896 Sept. 16; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1910 July 20
    - To Boas, 1912 May 12
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Apr. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Dec. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 June 2; 2p.
  - León (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 31
    - (See Boas, F. to Engerrand, Jorge, Oct. 31, 1913)
  - Leon, Luis G. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1911 Oct. 23; 1p.
  - León, M. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1912 Jan. 3; 1p.
  - Leon, Nicolas (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Apr. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Jan. 9; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Dec.; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Sept. 4; postcard
    - To Boas, 1913 Sept. 13; postcard
  - Leonard, O. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1934 June 11; 1p.
  - K. Leopold-Carolin. Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1927 Aug. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 23; 1p.
    - see also Loeffler
  - Leopoldina German Academy (Box 55)
    - See Walther, Johannes to the Amer. members of the Imperial Leopoldina German Academy, 1927 Mar.
  - Lerchenfeld-Koffering, Ethel (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1923; 2p.
  - Lerchenfeld-Koffering, Hugo (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 19; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 25; 2p.
  - Lerustrous, A. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1914 Nov. 11
  - Leskien, A. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1889 Dec. 24
  - Lesniowski, S. von (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1899 Apr. 7; 2p.
  - Lesser, Alexander (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1928 June 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 May 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Sept. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Oct. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 May 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Sept. 10; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Aug. 16; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Sept. 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Oct. 29; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - See From Boas, F. to Weltfish, G., June 3, 1932.
    - See Boas, F. open letter 1933 Dec., 1934 Feb. 21; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1935 June 22; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. open letter Nov. 30, 1937., 1939 Dec.; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Feb. 6; 1p.
  - Lesser, Mrs. Alexander (Box 55)
    See Weltfish, Gene.
  - Lesser, B.H. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1928 Sept. 15; 1p.
  - Lessing, Ada (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1936 June 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1936 May 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Sept. 2; 2p.
    - A. Lessing -- to R. Scharfstein, 1936 June 12; 2p.
  - Lessing, Ferdinand D. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 May 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 May 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 May 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 May 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Apr. 23; 1p.
    - (Enc: Lessing, F.D. to Graves, M. Apr. 23, 1939), 1939 May 13; 1p.
    - F.D. Lessing -- to M. Graves, 1939 Apr. 23; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Lessing, F.D., Apr. 23, 1939)
  - Lessing, O.E. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 23; 1p.
  - Lessing, P. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 12; 1p.
  - Lessing League (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 July 27; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 14; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 29; 1p
    - (See Brandes, S.F. Nov. 8, 1933. Enc. with Boas, F. to Brandes, S.F. Nov. 21, 1933.), 1934 Dec.
  - Lesson, B.W. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 4; 1p.
      See Leeson, B.W.
  - Lester, P. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 18; 1p.
  - Lester, Robert M. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1928 Apr. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 13; 1p.
    - R.M. Lester -- to N.M. Butler, 1939 Apr. 10; 1p.
  - Lestoque, Albert (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1p.
    - (Enc. with Johnson, Alvin, Aug. 19, 1940)
  - "Letters" (Box 55)
    - See Potter, J.C. -, 7-2-36
  - Leupp, F.E. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1910 Aug. 9
    - To Boas, 1910 Aug. 6
  - Leuschner, A.C. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 8; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 25; 1p.
  - Levene, P.A. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1921 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Mar. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Mar. 29; 1p.
  - Levene, R. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 13; 1p.
  - Leverett, F. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 21; 1p.
  - Levi, M. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1941 Apr. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Apr. 20; 2p.
  - Lévi-Strauss, Claude (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1942 Apr. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Apr. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Aug. 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Aug. 31; 1p.
  - Levin, N.W. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1933 May 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Sept. 27; 1p.
  - Levine, M.C. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 26; 1p.
  - Levine, P. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 3; 1p.
  - Levinger, Alfred (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 17; 1p.
  - Levinskaya, Maria (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1940 May 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 May 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 26; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1940 May 6; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1940 May 13; 1p.
  - Levinsky, C. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 18; 1p.
  - Levinson, I. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1920 Dec. 20; 1p.
  - Levinson, S.C. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 4p.
    - (Enc. with Barrett, H.J., Mar. 1, 1933)
  - Levy (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1926 Nov. 12; 1p.
  - Levy, A. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1904 Dec. 2; 1p.
  - Levy, Ernst (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 18; 4p.
  - Levy, Fritz (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 23; 1p.
  - Levy, M.P. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1932 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - (Enc: Levy, M.P. to Stowell, E.C. Apr. 7, 1932.), 1932 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - M.P. Levy -- to E.C. Stowell, 1932 Apr. 7; 1p.
  - Lévy Brühl, L. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1927 May 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 June 18; 2p.
  - Levysohn, Arthur (Box 55)
    - See Berliner Tageblatt, 1884.
  - Lewin, Albert (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 25; 2p.
  - Lewin, L. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1922 Mar. 14; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1922 Dec. 25; 1p.
  - Lewinski, Karl von (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927? Mar. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 July 10; teleg.
    - To Boas, 1932 end; 1p.
  - Lewinski-Corwin, Edward H. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1916 June 24
    - From Boas, 1920 Jan. 28; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1916 June 26
    - To Boas, 1916 June 29
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 19; 1p.
  - Lewinson, Leah (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 14; 1p.
  - Lewis, Albert B. (Box 56)
    - From Boas, 1905 June 12
    - From Boas, 1905 Oct. 3